♪ ♪
HAWKINS : Doctor , get back in the car !
SARTAIN : No ! No .
HAWKINS : I 'm still gonna blow this motherfucker 's brains out .
( Sartain yells )
- KAREN : Mom ! Mom ! - ( banging )
Help !
( tires screeching )
( insects chirping and buzzing )
- ( line ringing ) - CAMERON : Pick up .
Pick up .
Dude , where are you ?
OSCAR ( recorded ) : Hey there , sassy lovers .
- This is Oscar . - CAMERON : Damn it .
OSCAR : I am unable to take your call right now
because I 'm standing right ...
- behind you ! - ( phone beeps )
Hey , Oscar , uh , call me wh-when you get this .
Um , I messed up with Allyson , man .
I got to find her and , uh , fix it somehow ,
so , uh , if you know where she is
or if you guys are together , let me know .
All right . Be safe . Bye .
Damn it !
♪ ♪
Dude , you okay ?
Hey ! You okay ?
Hey .
Hey , man , I 'm coming . I 'm coming .
Oh , no .
Oh , my God . Okay .
Okay . ( muttering )
Help ! Help !
Oh , shit . Help !
Somebody help !
Okay , okay .
All right .
All right . Um , okay , okay , okay .
- ( grunts , coughs ) - ( gasps )
Okay . All right , man .
Come on . Come on , look at me , look at me .
Stay with me , stay with me .
Hawkins , Officer Hawkins .
Okay . Look at me , look at me . You 're good .
Hold on tight . I 'm gonna get help , okay ?
- Help ! Help ! - ( straining ) : He needs to die .
He needs to die . ( groans )
Okay , okay . Come on , come on .
Stay still , stay still , stay still . Look at me .
- Look at ... Look at me . - He needs to die .
Who needs to die ?
He needs to die .
And I 'm the one ...
that 's gonna get him .
( siren blaring )
Oh , shit .
Haddonfield Sheriff 's Department .
Stop right there .
I said stop !
( gasping breaths )
Shit .
( softly ) : Shit .
- PETE : Hawkins ! You all right ? - ( whimpers )
- ( Hawkins sighs ) - Did you see him ?
- Where did he go ? - Where have you guys been ?
I called for backup ten minutes ago .
SULLIVAN : Easy , rookie .
Loomis said he shot him multiple times in the chest .
I saw from 50 yards away .
He crossed right here and then just disappeared .
Okay . Sullivan , you and Tobias
search Chestnut , south to the bypass .
Hawkins and I will track Market Street up to Lampkin .
We 'll catch him .
Yeah , kill the bad guy .
Jesus , Frank .
I used to know the guy .
- Michael . We were kids . - Yeah ?
Was he one of those weirdo freaks who used to pluck
the wings off butterflies when he was a kid ?
Not that I ever saw .
He was just ...
Just killed his sister when he was six years old ?
Yeah . My mom used to make me go over to his house to play .
She felt bad . But he would just spend the whole time
staring out of his sister 's bedroom window .
I always remember thinking ,
" The hell is he looking at out there ? "
He was looking at Haddonfield .
Simple town where nothing exciting ever happens .
PETE : Yeah .
Then one day , he just snapped .
♪ ♪
- ( singsongy ) : Lonnie , Lonnie , weird and scrawny . - ( laughing )
Has bad dreams , so cries to mommy .
BOY : He 's gonna get you .
He 's gonna get you , Lonnie . He 's gonna get you .
Touch Conrad 's candy again ,
I swear to God I 'll beat your ugly ass !
Yeah , we 'll beat your ugly ass . That 's right !
I didn 't do it . It wasn 't me .
- It was Richie . - Then show me .
Open your hand right now .
- No . - Why don 't you open up your hand ?
I don 't want to .
- Get off . - Open your hand !
( grunting )
Leave me alone .
BOY : Yeah , okay .
( groans , grunts )
That 's what you get when you fuck with the Mullanys .
Get away from me ! Leave me alone !
( siren blaring )
Hey . Everything all right with you kids ?
Yeah . Just trick-or-treating with our new old friend Lonnie .
What ? You ...
You kids see anyone walking around in a white mask ?
It 's Halloween . Everyone 's wearing a mask .
That 's right . I need you to go home right now .
Go home to your parents and lock your doors .
- Why ? What did he do ? - What did he do ?
He murdered three teenagers down the street .
( siren blaring )
( singsongy ) : Don 't get murdered , Lonnie .
- ( laughter ) - Sleep with one eye open , Lonnie .
He 's gonna get you , Lonnie Elam !
- Boogey , Boogey . - Did you see his face ?
GIRL : Lonnie , Lonnie , weird and scrawny .
Has bad dreams , so cries to mommy .
Be careful , Lonnie .
BOY : He 's gonna get you , Lonnie . He 's gonna get you .
GIRL : He 's gonna get you , Lonnie .
Sleep with one eye open , Lonnie .
BOY : He 's gonna get you , Lonnie .
GIRL : He 's gonna get you , Lonnie Elam .
( panting )
( grunts )
( groaning )
( gasping breaths )
♪ ♪
Help . ( whimpers )
Help !
( crying ) : I 'm sorry for tripping Tommy Doyle
and bullying him .
Just ... just-just please don 't kill me .
- ( yelps ) - Hey , kid . You okay ?
Hey , whoa . It 's all right . Take it easy .
Where 'd he go ?
Where is he ?
You-you didn 't see him ?
- Take a deep breath . - Who ?
The Boogeyman .
♪ ♪
- He 's gonna kill you ! - Whoa . Hey , hey .
- Boogeyman ? - What the hell ?
That 's it .
That 's the Myers house .
That 's where it happened .
Halloween , 1963 .
♪ ♪
( creaking )
- ( groans ) - PETE : Hey , Frank ?
Yeah .
There 's a dead dog in here .
What ?
Nothing .
( flies buzzing )
( groans )
( door creaks , bangs )
Don 't shoot !
- ( whispers ) : Frank . Frank . - What ?
Oh , sh ...
Go for it .
PETE ( whispers ) : Three , two , one .
( sighs ) : Okay .
- Crazy . - ( thumping )
Ugh .
Spiderwebs .
♪ ♪
( wind whistling )
( chuckles softly )
Haddonfield .
Where nothing exciting ever happ ...
( yells , gasps )
McCabe ?
( Pete groaning )
HAWKINS : McCabe ?
- McCabe ! - ( gasping )
Drop him !
Drop him or I 'll shoot .
Michael , I 'm warning you .
( gasping )
Goddamn it !
( gun fires )
( gasping )
( thuds )
( gun firing )
( Pete gasping )
Hang on , McCabe .
Pete . Pete , Pete .
Hey , hey . It 's-it 's okay .
( stammering ) : We 're gonna get ...
We 're gonna get you some help , okay ? Just hang in there .
- It 's gonna be okay , all right ? - ( siren wailing )
- You 're gonna stay with me ? - ( tires squeal )
- Yeah . Yeah . - Stay with me , okay ?
LOOMIS : Stay back ! The evil is here !
( car door closes )
- OFFICER : Move , move , move ! - ( indistinct radio chatter )
- Freeze ! - Stop !
LOOMIS : Michael , stay where you are .
PETE : You got him , right ?
We ... Tell me we got him .
OFFICER ( outside ) : Stay right there !
Uh-huh .
We got him ?
HAWKINS ( crying ) : Oh , my God .
I 'm sorry .
Sorry .
Oh , God .
♪ ♪
LOOMIS : Stop !
Michael , stay back .
OFFICER : Hold it right there !
( over radio ) : ... description of the subject for confirmation .
- It 's him . - It 's him .
( distorted ) : It 's Michael Myers .
Officer Hawkins , tell me , what happened in here ?
Tell me what happened .
Did Michael kill ?
Did Michael kill again ?
( panting )
♪ ♪
( John Carpenter 's Halloweentheme playing )
( " She Doesn 't Want You Anymore " playing )
WOMEN : ♪ Daddy don 't take it hard ♪
♪ When you cry ... ♪
MARCUS : I thought that was gonna be , like ,
a holiday pizza party
with a bunch of coworkers , not an orgy .
Your vulgar-ass boss acted inappropriately .
You need to start
standing up for yourself in these situations .
Yeah , no . That 's right . You 're right .
No , stand up for myself . Now , tomorrow morning ,
I 'm gonna go in there , I 'm gonna quit that job ...
And you 're gonna punch Dr. Mathis in the face .
- LINDSEY : Ooh ! Champagne . - Yep . Punch him in the face .
- Okay . - LONNIE : Yes ! - MARION : Oh , look at you .
TOMMY : With all the shit happening today ,
- two homicides at a gas station ... - ( cork pops )
LONNIE : Stop it . We don 't even know if he was on the bus .
MARION : Tommy , you 're so paranoid .
( laughter )
- LONNIE : Very sous bois . - Mm , okay . ( laughs )
- Oh . Excuse me . - Great .
LONNIE : Yeah , that 's ... that 's a little old French term
meaning this bitch tastes good .
( laughter )
All right !
( loud laughter )
Hey . Hey .
Hey , hey , guys , guys , guys .
Can you bring it down a tad ?
Like , my wife and I are trying to watch the talent show .
LONNIE : Yeah , of course . Yeah .
- Sorry . - Yeah . Yeah , sorry . - Sorry about that .
- Appreciate it . - TOMMY : Okay .
( laughter )
I 'm gonna go get us a couple of drinks .
- You relax . - Okay .
LONNIE : Well , I 'm kind of a sommelier , but for cheap wines .
- Yeah . - Yeah , can I get , um ,
two of the voodoo skeleton thing right here ?
Hey , look here , don 't be bothered by them motherfuckers
over there , man .
They are friends with that crazy lady
that almost got killed by Michael Myers .
No shit . I-I heard about that .
Wha ... Uh , Laura Stropes or something .
- Laurie Strode . - Strode , yeah .
The one that survived Michael Myers .
They come here every Halloween ,
and , you know , tears in their beers . ( laughs )
( applause )
Ladies and gentlemen , I would like to introduce
our next thespian .
Now , I used to bust this guy 's balls when we were kids ,
but he is all grown-up now .
And he 's become the most captivating bird whistler .
( laughter , whooping , whistling )
- Hey , everybody . - WOMAN : All right , Tommy !
Uh , Lonnie put me up to this shit .
( laughter )
Uh , I 'm not gonna whistle for you .
I 'm , uh ... I 'm gonna tell you a story .
- WOMAN : Ghosts and goblins ! - Oh ... ( laughs )
- MARION : You got this , Tommy ! - MAN : Turn off the lights !
Any of you know the story of the Haddonfield Boogeyman ?
Too young to give a shit ? Too drunk to remember ?
40 years ago , a madman escaped from a mental hospital .
It was the night before Halloween ,
and three teenage girls
were walking home from Haddonfield High .
They had sightings of a ...
a ghostlike figure creeping right through our town .
A man in a white mask .
Or was it more than a man ?
He was watching them .
Before the night was over , three people would be murdered .
And in the house next door , there was a babysitter
and a young boy and a young girl ,
and they were brutally attacked by this stalker
who had a power beyond any mortal man .
My name is Tommy Doyle .
And I was that young boy .
So , please , join me
in commemorating the victims
and the survivors of Michael Myers .
- ( whistling , whooping ) - Thank you .
Now , we have , uh , the lovely Miss Lindsey Wallace .
Her babysitter , Annie Brackett , was executed that night .
( muffled scream )
TOMMY : And we have Miss Marion Chambers .
She survived an assault .
( screams )
We have Lonnie Elam .
Lonnie survived a face-to-face encounter .
Help !
It 's Halloween night in Haddonfield .
When terror 's supposed to be fun .
When we hide behind masks
and we pretend we aren 't what we are .
Is he real ?
Who knows ?
Who 's next ?
Maybe not tonight , maybe not tomorrow ,
but the Boogeyman is coming for me .
And he 's coming for you .
But he 's not gonna get us .
Not this time .
Because we will never succumb to fear .
This is for you , Laurie .
( cheering , applause )
Wherever you are .
KAREN : We 're almost at the hospital , Mom .
Take deep breaths . Deep breaths .
We 're almost there . We 're almost at the hospital .
You 're gonna be okay . You 're gonna be okay .
It 's good . It 's good .
- It 's okay . It 's okay . - ( sirens whoop , horn drones )
LAURIE : No , no , no , no .
- No , no , no , no , no ! - No !
Oh , let it burn !
No !
Let it burn !
MAN ( over radio ) : Copy that . Utilities are being shut down .
BENTON : We got a gas-fed fire in here .
( over radio ) : Ten-four . Stand by .
Copy .
( over radio ) : Assignment complete .
- Utilities are disengaged . - Copy .
- Eyes on the roof . - Watch out .
With you . Let 's move . All right , let 's go .
( over radio ) : Command Ladder 13 , do you copy ?
( firefighter shouting indistinctly )
( screams )
( gasping , coughing )
- ( alarm whooping ) - Mayday . Mayday .
( coughing )
( over radio ) : Radio silence . We have a Mayday alert .
This is Benton with Engine Eight .
There 's been a structural collapse .
My air supply has been compromised .
PASS alarm has been activated .
( coughs ) Oh , shit .
( over radio ) : Come in , Engine 13 .
BENTON : Oh . There 's someone else down here !
( over radio ) : Do you copy ?
( Benton screams )
( over radio ) : Central , we have a firefighter down .
All right , team one , commence rescue .
Benton ?
Benton , my hand 's here !
Take my hand !
Take my hand now !
( over radio ) : Mayday event . Send in rescue team now .
Grab my hand !
( screaming )
The fuck is that ?
♪ ♪
( breathing heavily )
( firefighter grunts , groans )
( pained yelling )
( screaming )
KAREN : Mom , can you hear us ?
- EMT : All right . - She was stabbed in the abdomen .
EMT : Activate the trauma team . We got an unconscious female
- with an abdominal injury . - KAREN : Can you hear me , Mom ?
EMT : Possibly penetrating , multiple contusions .
KAREN : Mom , can you hear me ?
She 's losing a lot of blood .
Ma 'am , can you tell me your name ?
Allyson , wait here , honey .
( panting ) : Um , uh , that 's ... that 's my mom .
It 's Laurie Strode .
- Strode . She was attacked . - Laurie .
KAREN : She 's , uh ... she 's my mom .
Sh-She 's been attacked . She has probably ...
Ma 'am , I-I think you should really let a nurse look at you .
I 'm fine .
( shuddering ) : I 'm fine .
It 's not my blood .
Okay ? It 's not my blood .
♪ ♪
( trembling breaths )
( whimpers softly )
( indistinct chatter )
( muffled sobbing )
DOCTOR ( muffled ) : We 'll close up the fascia ,
and , uh , we 'll loosely staple the , uh , skin
so it doesn 't get infected .
( chatter continues indistinctly )
She 's lost a good bit of blood , but it 's all controllable .
I think she 'll be fine .
Get her to the floor , into the ICU tonight .
The internal organ will be repaired ,
and so there shouldn 't be any long-term damage .
Her only concern will be
her abdominal wall will be very sore from the knife wound
and from our midline incision here .
KAREN : Thank you for everything .
Honey .
Hey .
She 's gonna be okay .
( both sighing )
Dad 's gone .
He 'll always be with us .
Even if we can 't see him .
( siren blaring )
( siren fades in distance )
WOMAN ( on TV ) : No , I 'm not afraid to go .
I just don 't feel like it .
Besides , I sort of promised my father
we-we were going to the movies .
I don 't hear no more fire trucks .
Goddamn sleep apnea mask smells like Lucky Strikes
from when your mother borrowed it .
I smell it , too .
But that stink ain 't cigarettes .
That 's Laurie Strode 's house on fire .
Well , from-from upstairs , it looks like they put it out .
But that nut bag lives a highly flammable lifestyle .
Better not talk no shit about that woman .
She will fuck you up .
PHIL : How about you and I snack on some Cheez-Its
and try a little Beaujolais nouveau ?
Cheap piece of shit . ( sighs )
You don 't know how to fly that thing .
Give me that controller .
- Here , I got you . - ( motor sputtering )
The fuck was that ?
Somebody in there ?
( clattering )
Hey !
SONDRA ( whispers ) : You see anything ?
( screams )
Hey , Sondra . Sondra .
There 's a big fella in our bathroom ,
and he 's wearing a monster mask .
Well , what the fuck does he want ?
Who gives a shit ? Call the cops !
( screams )
( grunting )
( screaming )
( Phil screaming )
PHIL : Run , Sondra ! Run !
( Sondra screams )
( sobbing )
( sobbing ) : No .
Please no .
( Sondra screams , sobs )
Fuck ...
( screams )
( strained gasping )
( Sondra coughs )
- ( body thuds ) - PHIL : Sondra !
( glass shatters )
( Phil whimpering )
Sondra !
( gasping )
( body squeaking on floor )
( Phil groaning )
Sondra !
- ( thudding ) - ( Phil grunts )
( footsteps )
( blade scrapes )
♪ ♪
- ( blade scrapes ) - ( Sondra whimpers )
( grunts weakly )
( blade scrapes )
( knife thuds )
( Sondra gasps weakly )
- ( applause ) - ( audience laughing )
♪ I think I 'll break off with my girlfriend ♪
♪ Her antics are queer , I 'll admit ♪
♪ Each time I say , " Darling , I love you " ♪
♪ She tells me that I 'm full of sh ... ♪
♪ Shaving cream ♪
- ♪ Be nice and clean ... ♪ - ( laughter )
Hey . I , uh , heard your speech up there , man .
Like , everybody knows that story ,
everybody is terrified of that Boogeyman shit ,
- and I had no idea . - No , I appreciate it .
Yeah . Hey , man , let me ... let me buy you guys a round .
- Drink ? Drink ? Yeah . - Appreciate it , man . Thank you .
- Sorry about that earlier , too . - No , no , no , it 's fine .
- It 's fine . We 're all good here . - Hey , let me see that .
- MARION : I 'm a nurse . - MARCUS : Oh , okay .
Is he a real doctor ? ( chuckles )
- Oh . Thank you . Cheers , Tommy . - Cheers .
- LINDSEY : Yeah . - MARION : Let me check you out .
♪ I stepped in a big pile of shit , shit , shit , shit ♪
- ( laughter ) - ♪ Be nice and clean ♪
- ( cell phone buzzing ) - ♪ Shave every day ♪
♪ And you 'll always look keen ... ♪
Hey there , Bonnie .
You and Clyde need a ride ?
CAMERON : Dad , I need you to come pick me up .
I 'm , uh ... I 'm-I 'm at the park near school ,
and , uh , a police officer was attacked .
- And , uh ... - Where-where are you ?
( indistinct radio chatter )
♪ ♪
EMT : Keep applying pressure to external hemorrhage .
EMT 2 : How 's that pulse ?
I 've been having a bar about 50 years .
- 50 years ? - And you started with your granddaddy , right ?
Yeah , my grandpa who started the business .
That 's my grandpa 's picture up here . Yeah , I got ...
I got my bat up here . Huckleberry .
- Old Huckleberry . - Baseball bat . Excellent .
Oh , if he come back today , we gonna ...
- we got something for him . - That 's right .
- LINDSEY : To Brian . To Brian . - Yeah .
- TOMMY : To Brian . - LINDSEY : To Brian .
- VANESSA : Thank you . Yes . - All right , then .
I knew we came to the right place .
Hey , guys . Cameron 's in trouble .
Lonnie , what 's wrong ?
Oh , my God .
( indistinct radio chatter )
Got a goddamn massacre on our hands .
- Graham ! - Yes , sir .
Establish a perimeter .
Copy that .
Motherfucker !
GRAHAM ( over speaker ) : Attention , all responders .
Be advised , we have a violent criminal at large ,
armed and dangerous .
We will deploy all units
of frontline and tactical officers to search the area .
This fugitive is on foot .
His name is Michael Myers .
Go get him .
♪ Julia Butterfly ♪
- ♪ Lived in a tree ♪ - ( cell phones chiming )
( phones continue chiming , ringing )
♪ Over two years in a bucket ♪
♪ She pooped and she peed ... ♪
- Oh , my God . - WOMAN : Hey , turn it up .
MARION : Tommy , look . Hey , turn it up .
REPORTER : ... service station earlier today .
This evening , four bodies were discovered
in three homes along the same residential street .
Residents of North Haddonfield are on high alert .
- Officials are investigating . - MARION : What 's gonna stop him ?
REPORTER : Less than an hour ago ,
Haddonfield authorities positively identified ...
- That 's our street . - ... several more victims
in this South Bastick neighborhood .
MARCUS : That reporter is right outside Mrs. Dewbottom 's house .
That 's right next door to our house .
REPORTER : ... two patients of the local
Smith 's Grove State Hospital unaccounted for
after yesterday 's transport bus escape .
Authorities have not confirmed a connection
between those two events , but police are encouraging
all residents to remain inside
until further information is released .
Tonight 's tragedy an eerie reminder of an event
in Haddonfield history
this community has spent decades trying to forget .
But police now believe that more people ...
I-I remember him from 40 years ago .
I was laying in my bed , and he ...
he stabbed ... he ... he killed her .
That 's-that 's Julian . That 's that ...
That 's that little asshole kid from across the street .
And she was my number-one main best babysitter .
Yeah , we 're gonna go , all right ?
Uh , hey , thanks , man .
Um , it was nice meeting you guys , but we got to go .
- MARION : Be careful . - BRIAN : Oh , y 'all be careful , now .
What the hell is happening ?
It 's Michael . It 's got to be .
WOMAN ( on TV ) : I 've lived here my whole life .
This was a safe place , and now it 's not anymore .
Shit . I forgot my stethoscope .
Come on , baby , we got to get home .
I bet that lady still has it . Hey , I 'll be right back .
( scoffs )
( alarm beeps , lock clicks )
( keys jingling )
( screams )
What ?
( whimpers , screams )
- What 's wrong ? - ( whimpers )
Baby . Baby , baby .
- What ? What ? What 's wrong ? - He 's in the car .
- What ? - He 's in the car .
- Who ? What ? - He 's in the back seat .
Michael Myers is in the back seat . Go look .
- Go look ? Hell no ! - ( grunts )
What 's wrong with you ?
♪ ♪
Somebody help me . He 's here .
He 's in the back seat of my car .
I saw him when I went to go get in .
It 's the same guy you were talking about ...
- the one that that was on TV . - ( patrons murmuring )
LINDSEY : Tommy , what are you doing ?
That nasty snatcher 's in my parking lot ?
TOMMY : Yes , sir .
Love lives today .
But evil dies tonight .
BRIAN : Tommy Doyle 's gonna fuck him up .
MARCUS : He 's right there , in my car .
He , uh ... he got out of the car
and got into the front of the car .
I saw him . He looked right at me .
♪ ♪
( car engine starts )
MARION : Is it him ?
He 's watching us .
I got this .
LINDSEY : Tommy , be careful .
( over car radio ) : ♪ Figaro , Figaro ♪
♪ Figaro , Figaro , Figaro ♪
♪ Figaro , Figaro , Figaro , Figaro ♪
♪ Figaro ... ♪
♪ Ahimè , ahimè ♪
♪ Che furia ♪
♪ Ahimè , che folla ... ♪
( cycling through radio stations )
Michael .
Wake up .
- ( onlookers gasping ) - LINDSEY : Oh , my God .
- Tommy , careful ! - MARCUS : Oh , no !
- Whoa , whoa , whoa , whoa ! - Whoa !
( onlookers shouting , gasping )
( tires squealing )
BRIAN : Damn . What in the hell 's going on ?
( car speeding away )
( crash )
( over car radio ) : ♪ Play guitar ♪
( electrical crackling )
♪ Then when we came down ... ♪
( group murmuring )
MARCUS : Fuck !
Come on , come on .
MARCUS : Look at my damn car .
ANNOUNCER ( over radio ) : WURG 94.9 .
LINDSEY : Tommy , careful !
ANNOUNCER : Giving you the urge with Willie the Kid .
Haddonfield 's home for rock .
He thinks he can come around here and scare us ?
- ( man grunts ) - ( crowd murmuring )
( groans )
I 'm gonna rip his mask off , look him in the eye ,
swing Old Huckleberry here and say night night .
( panting )
Night night .
( crickets chirping )
( dog barking in distance )
( " It 's Halloween " by Pete Antell playing )
( singing along ) : ♪ The goblins will get you ♪
♪ If you don 't watch out ♪
♪ They 'll take you and shake you until you shout ♪
♪ Stop , look and listen ♪
♪ It 's Halloween ... ♪
( song continues in other room )
Mmm .
Hey , Big John .
Hey , Big John !
♪ There 's witches and broomsticks ♪
♪ And big black hats ♪
♪ Stirrin ' up their potions in big black vats ... ♪
Could you turn that down ?
Christ , Little John .
I thought we were gonna watch a movie .
- No . - ( lowers music volume )
Fuck that .
It 's Halloween .
Pulled some old spooky records .
Want to get high and dance ?
It 's tempting .
( doorbell rings )
Little late for trick-or-treaters .
- Argh , matey . - Me and my sister were trick-or-treating ,
and , uh , we got candy bars from your house ,
and when she bit into it , there was a rusty razor blade .
Wha ... All right . Calm down , calm down .
Now , where is she ?
She 's right , um ... there .
( Little John gasps )
Big John !
Big John , come quick !
BIG JOHN : What , what , what , what ?
- What 's happened ? - She 's bleeding .
She swallowed a razor blade . She 's still alive .
- Call 911 . - Can you help her ?
- Oh . - She bit her tongue off .
- She 's bleeding to death . - Okay , there 's the blade .
- It 's in the barf . - ( door slams )
( gasps )
BIG JOHN : The fuck was that ?
Did someone just go in our house ?
( quiet footsteps , rustling )
Oh , my God .
- What is it ? What ? - Are you okay ?
- Boo ! - Aah ! Jesus !
- We scared you ! - ( laughing )
I got it !
You think this is funny , huh ?
We got you good .
I stole the whole damn bowl .
( laughing )
You don 't know who you 're messing with , do you ?
Take it easy , Big John .
- They 're too young to know . - Too young to know what ?
Do you have any idea whose house this was ?
No .
You ever hear of Michael fucking Myers ?
And do you know what happens to people
who come into the Myers home without an invitation ?
We 're not even scared .
- Oh , yeah ? - Oh , yeah .
He stabbed his sister in the tits .
- MINDY : Yuck . - Right upstairs .
And sometimes , when the wind blows just right ,
we can still hear her ghost
calling out his name .
Oh , sh-she calls .
Mm-hmm .
( whispers ) : Michael .
BOTH ( singsongy ) : Michael ...
Get out of my yard , you little perverts !
- ( kids screaming ) - ( Little John yells )
( Big John chuckling )
- ( dogs barking in distance ) - CHRISTY : Wh-What was that ?
♪ ♪
All right , let 's go . Let 's get him into code room three .
- What have we got here ? - Internal bleeding ,
lacerations , but he 's gonna make it .
Call Respiratory for a ventilator .
- Officer Hawkins . - Go . Go , go , go .
Make sure trauma two is prepped .
And I need help getting him on the table .
Allyson . Allyson .
Hey . Can I speak with you ?
Ask you a few questions ?
( indistinct announcement over P.A. )
I was always told that I couldn 't ...
I couldn 't talk about Michael .
I could never acknowledge the tragedy .
It was as if my mother 's biggest fear
was that my grandmother was right
and the Boogeyman was real .
KAREN : For 40 years , he was waiting
to come and kill my mother .
He found where she lived .
He came to her house .
She put us in his path .
He murdered my husband .
That 's what happened .
GRAHAM : Well , so how did Michael know ?
How did he know how to find your grandmother ?
He didn 't .
It was his doctor .
Michael 's doctor .
He is the one that ...
He took him there . He knew where to go .
And he 's the one that brought them together .
It was his obsession ,
not Michael 's .
KAREN : But we got him .
Shot him in the face , burned him alive
so he can 't hurt anyone ever again .
( inhales deeply )
I 'm sorry , Karen .
Thank you .
No one told you ?
Told me what ?
Michael Myers is alive .
What ? !
Allyson , Allyson ! Allyson , are you okay ?
- ( stammers ) Oh , sorry . - MAN : Slow down .
- Allyson , please wait . - ALLYSON : Excuse me . Excuse me .
I 'm so sorry . I just want to help in any way I can , okay ?
- He 's still alive . - We 're going after him .
Me , my dad , you , if you want to come .
- We 're joining Tommy Doyle . - ( shuddering )
KAREN : You need to get everybody here now .
If he is alive , he is on his way here .
Mom .
Honey , I want you to go and sit in Grandmother 's room
and wait there until she wakes up , okay ?
- No . - No , no , no . She-she 's coming with us .
- We 're joining Tommy Doyle . - She what ?
I don 't know if you 've heard , but they 've ...
No , the police officers should be on their way here right now .
Tommy 's organizing groups , groups of people that care .
We 're gonna go after him . We 're gonna find Michael .
I 'm going with them . We 're gonna hunt him down ,
- and we 're gonna put an end to this . - CAMERON : Yeah .
No , he is on his way here . I keep telling them that .
He is stalking her , and we are staying here to protect her .
He 's infected your family , he 's infected my family
with grief and fear for 40 years .
He 's gonna die tonight .
- He killed Dad . - EMT : Clear the hallway ! You have to move !
WOMAN : Excuse me ! My husband , he 's been very badly hurt !
- ( groaning ) - Clear the hallway , people .
Go back to the waiting area .
Go back to the waiting room . Clear the hallway .
I 'm not gonna pretend this didn 't happen .
I love Dad , and somebody loves
whoever is laying under those sheets right now .
Look . Look at me . We failed , baby .
We set a trap , we set the whole thing on fire ,
and he lived through it . Think about that .
The police are out there looking for him .
You think you 're the one that 's gonna find him ?
Sit in that room and wait with your grandmother .
Now !
( trembling breaths )
♪ ♪
Does the hospital have security guards ?
Do you have security guards ?
It seems like you should have security guards
in case something like this happens .
And this is happening right now .
I mean , my daughter is in here , my mother is in here ,
there is a madman on the loose ...
KAREN : Oh ! Oh , God !
( screaming )
LAURIE : Goodbye , Michael .
♪ ♪
This is for you , whenever you need it .
( quiet chatter )
She 's here . She 's here . We found her . Laurie 's here .
She 's in recovery .
It 's lucky she survived .
I just heard from one of the police officers
at her compound .
11 dead bodies . They 're all first responders .
Holy shit . Cameron 's in there .
Three of his friends were killed .
- It 's a madhouse . - All right , Lonnie , listen .
The only way we 're gonna stop this
is if we all come together on this .
You 're goddamn right .
- All right . All right . - All right ?
LONNIE : How about this sassy tackle ?
You have a permit for all these ?
Some of ' em .
- CAMERON : Dad . - LONNIE : Hey , hey .
- Where 's your girlfriend ? - Uh , she 's okay .
- She 's gonna stay with her family . - Good for her .
- Hey , Mr. Doyle . - Hey , buddy .
- Lonnie , check it out . - ( vehicle approaching )
LONNIE : You guys are coming , too ?
Couldn 't let you have all the fun .
MARCUS : So many victims in our neighborhood .
Close friends of ours , and we just want to help out .
I 'm a doctor . My husband 's a nurse .
I should 've guessed .
All right , we have to give all these people protection .
- You got to share your shit , Lonnie . - All right .
CAMERON : You coming with us ?
Let 's see what you got .
LONNIE : Yeah , just help yourself .
Michael Myers has haunted this town for 40 years .
Tonight , we hunt him down .
♪ ♪
( engine roars , tires squeal )
Excuse me . I need some good people .
People who aren 't afraid to get their hands dirty .
Everybody else needs to go home .
CAMERON : So , what do we do if we find him ?
ALLYSON : Go inside . Go inside .
It 's not safe to be out . Go .
It 's not safe to be out .
Man , I had an altercation with Myers about an hour ago ,
but he escaped .
Now , listen , boys , there 's strength in numbers .
You cover Spring Creek to the bypass ,
and then let me know if you see anything .
This man is a threat , and we need to stop him tonight !
Nobody ever took him seriously .
- Who ? - Dr. Loomis ,
Michael 's first doctor .
He knew a killer when he saw one .
TOMMY : Now , the only way to catch him
is to play by his own game ... the element of surprise .
So he thinks you 're going one place ,
then you pop up someplace else .
And keep your eyes open .
Eyes open .
( engine starts )
Wait , what 's going on over there ?
MARCUS : Baby , who is that ?
VANESSA : Looks like kids .
They all alone ?
LINDSEY : Marion , give me the flashlight .
It 's the wrong night to be out .
Careful , Lindsey .
- Lindsey , I wouldn 't go ... - Stay here .
( swing creaking )
Never fired a gun before .
Right , so I don 't even know why they gave you a gun .
It 's big , too . Can you handle it ?
- ( Marcus sighs ) - That 's a no .
Give me , give me . I shot this shit before .
MARCUS : Okay . If you want it .
VANESSA : I got it .
MARCUS : Okay . Fine .
Hey .
What are you guys doing out here ?
It 's Halloween . We 've been trick-or-treating .
- We got a whole bag of candy . - You guys should not be
out here right now , okay ? It 's not safe .
- You gonna kill me ? - CHRISTY ( laughing ) : No .
Satan , not today .
- Oh , I 'm so scared . - Are you guys alone ?
- Where are your parents ? - CHRISTY : No .
No , we 're waiting for our friend .
And , like , there 's a creepy man in a white mask ,
and he keeps , like , trying to play hide-and-seek with us ,
- and he thinks ... ( laughs ) - And I think he 's a pervert .
Where did you see him ?
He 's just hiding behind trees .
And he pops out like , " Peekaboo ! "
I mean , we 're not three years old .
- Come on , man ! - Oh , look , there he is .
- Oh , hello ! - Hello .
MINDY ( laughs ) : What the hell are you doing ?
( Christy laughing )
MINDY : You want some candy ?
Is that Dennis 's mask ?
Run . Go home now .
Before he kills us all ! Get out of here !
Run ! Do not turn around !
Keep going home !
Oh , my God .
VANESSA : What if someone is disabled ?
- Like , that doesn 't make any sense ... - MARCUS : Yeah , but ...
- ( whimpers ) - What the hell is that ?
- What the fuck ? - It 's Michael .
( thumping )
( gasping )
( all screaming )
Fuck this bullshit ! Drive !
VANESSA : Go ! Go !
VANESSA : Drive the fucking ...
( all screaming )
God !
- ( lock clicks ) - ( frantic chatter )
- No , whoa ! Jesus , Marion . - Marion , watch it !
- Marion , the door 's locked ! - I don 't want to die in here !
- Unlock the door ! - Unlock the door ! - Oh !
- Come on ! - Let me out of here ! - Move ! He 's behind you !
- The door 's locked , Marion . - Move !
( screams )
( yells )
- ( screaming ) - ( groaning )
Go , go !
Vanessa , go !
Get out of the fucking car !
- I love you , baby ! - ( Marion screaming )
No ! ( groans )
- ( screaming ) - Let go of her !
- Okay , come on . We got to go . We got to go . - Oh , God .
MARION ( whimpers ) : No .
MARCUS : Shoot him ! Shoot him , Marion !
MARION : Hey , Michael .
This is for Dr. Loomis .
( gun clicking )
( whimpering )
- Oh , God . No ! - MARCUS : Marion !
( grunting )
Come on . Die .
Die , die , die !
( gasping weakly )
( groans )
( wheezing )
( breathing deeply )
( gunshots )
♪ ♪
( grunts )
( yelps , grunts )
( choking )
( panting )
( whimpering )
( breathing deeply )
( panting quietly )
( muffled whimper )
( sobs softly )
( muffled , gasping breaths )
( footsteps receding )
- ( Laurie groans , coughs ) - Mom . Oh , God . No , wait .
Stop , stop , please . Take it easy . Take it easy .
- I 'm fine . - You 're not fine .
You had a knife in your fucking stomach .
It 's a paper cut .
Where 's Allyson ?
She was supposed to be in here , with you .
- You didn 't see her ? - ( groans ) Nah ...
I 'm so geeked out on pain meds , kiddo .
Uh , uh , no .
Is everything okay ?
She probably just needed some fresh air .
My God , they just leave your bloody shirt just sitting here ?
Karen .
Michael 's gone .
We got him .
That 's right . We got him .
We burned him to the goddamn ground .
- ( door opens ) - NURSE : Excuse us .
Pardon .
- Uh , over here . - Frank ?
- EMT : Go a little further back . - NURSE : Okay . Okay .
- Got the draw sheet ? - Yeah .
EMT : One , two ...
- ( thudding ) - ( grunting ) : There you go .
NURSE : Okay .
You knew my dad ?
Yeah , I knew Ray .
He used to sell me peyote .
I remember once we were out on Lake Cherokee in this canoe
with a shaman from Little Rock .
( laughing ) : Your-your daddy got freaked out
by his own reflection .
He took off his pants , and he jumped in .
( laughing )
I stopped doing drugs with him ,
but I 'll-I 'll miss him .
- CAMERON : Dad . - LONNIE : What ? It 's true .
No , no , no . Dad , look , right there .
You see that ? That 's Tommy .
- LONNIE : Yeah . - CAMERON : Whose car is that ?
LONNIE : Lindsey 's . Shit .
Lindsey 's car .
It 's covered in blood . There 's no bodies .
It 's Michael .
He 's here .
Come on , I need you guys . Come on .
TOMMY : Be careful now , all right ?
Keep your heads up , eyes open .
CAMERON : Okay . Let 's go , let 's go .
TOMMY : Lindsey !
- CAMERON : Okay . - TOMMY : Just be safe , okay ?
ALLYSON : You , too . Lindsey !
CAMERON : Lindsey !
TOMMY : Lindsey !
- ALLYSON : Marion ! - LONNIE : Marion !
You guys be careful , okay ?
Keep your heads up .
Oh , shit , Tommy .
Oh , fuck .
( Tommy and Lonnie gasp )
Oh , God .
Fuck me .
Yo , Dad , Dad . What 's over there ?
We found something .
Oh , God .
Oh , I 'm sorry .
- That 's Marion , Lonnie . - He did this .
( crying ) : Oh , God , Marion .
Tommy , what the fuck ?
I 'm gonna get you .
Come and get it , man .
( whimpering nearby )
Over here .
She 's over here .
LINDSEY ( crying ) : I saw his face .
I saw everything .
He 's still out there .
- She 's lucky to be alive . - I saw him .
TOMMY : You saw his face ?
LINDSEY : He 's still out there , Tommy .
LONNIE : You 'll be okay , Lindsey .
You 're gonna be okay .
LINDSEY : He 's still out there .
Frank .
Frank , are you awake ?
Do you remember that night ?
At the bar ?
You know , I-I never said anything ,
' cause I couldn 't be sure .
I was so messed up .
But you helped me .
I always liked you .
♪ ♪
- You so crazy . - ( Laurie sighs )
Fuck you .
( chuckles )
Hi .
I remember that night .
Yeah .
I kissed you .
I remember .
You held my hand .
That was it .
Now , I was hoping for more .
But I knew you were sweet for ...
( groans softly )
Ben Tramer .
( Hawkins groans )
Frank .
We got him .
We killed Michael .
You ki ...
Well , it 's about time .
( laughs ) Ow .
- Ow . Don 't make me laugh . - ( door opens )
NURSE : Oh , good . You 're awake .
( Hawkins groans )
Now , on a scale from one to ten ,
what is your pain level , with ten being the worst ?
Number 11 .
NURSE : This will make the pain go away .
( groans )
Laurie .
Nurse , will you do me a favor ?
Help out my friend here .
Make it a double .
TOMMY : You stood up to that monster .
LINDSEY : I tried , Tommy .
You know , when we were kids ,
we used to all dare each other
to sneak into the old Myers house .
( Tommy chuckles softly )
Lonnie was the only one brave enough to do it .
LONNIE : I lied .
I never made it inside .
When they arrested Michael that night ,
I was telling my wife that my daughter was killed ,
so I wasn 't there to put a bullet in his brain ,
like we should have . This is no time for prudence .
How 'm I supposed to know if my brother 's alive or not ?
- I-I don 't know . - I 've been waiting here for over an hour .
Who the hell 's in charge here ?
Authorized medical and security personnel only .
There 's not enough medical or security help .
- He 's going to kill everybody ! - You need to relax .
We 've requested backup officers and medical staff
from Russellville and Eaton County for support ,
but no confirmation .
We can 't handle this scope a crime scene .
My son . My son Oscar , is he here ?
Uh , I got a call .
I 'm his mother . Is he alive ?
I have no idea , but triage expansion just opened up .
I 'm gonna have you sign in right here .
It 's spelled
B-E-R-L-U-C-C-H-I .
TOMMY : Clear the hallway , please .
Somebody help !
Please , emergency .
Take her to the emergency room , please .
You 're gonna be okay , Linds .
He 's still out there , Tommy .
- Be careful . - TOMMY : Karen .
How are you doing ? How 's your mom ?
- How 's Laurie ? Is she okay ? - Where 's my daughter ?
She 's okay . She 's fine .
She 's with Lonnie and Cameron .
No , no , but he 's coming here .
She 's not supposed to be with them .
He 's coming here ? How do you know that ?
All right , secure a perimeter . Hospital 's on lockdown .
- All right , listen , folks . Listen ! - ( clamoring )
Folks , please .
- The Boogeyman is at large . - ( clamoring quiets )
He 's got no choice but to emerge .
He is an apex predator .
When he surfaces , there will be no pause .
There will be no empathy .
This ends when Michael is dead !
Michael Myers will be executed tonight ,
and it will not go without witness !
We need all of you .
- Evil dies tonight ! - ( shouts of assent )
Evil dies tonight !
All right , everybody , calm down .
The Sheriff 's Department has this ...
No , no , no , no , no , no , no , no .
Sheriff , we will not calm down .
We have watched your department fail ...
- fail tonight ! - WOMAN : Tommy 's right !
This is Haddonfield .
This is our town .
He killed my daughter 40 years ago
and desecrated her body .
Evil dies tonight .
BARKER : Goddamn it , Brackett !
I am the law , not you .
- MAN : Fuck off , Barker . - Jonesy , get over there !
- Robin , I need you up there . - ( clamoring )
I need you over here . You two ...
- ( groans ) - TOMMY : Laurie !
- KAREN : Tommy , you can 't go in there ! - Tommy ?
- Tommy , you can 't go in there ! - Laurie . Laurie .
- KAREN : Tommy ! - Tommy .
- Laurie . He killed Marion . - Tommy .
- And he attacked Lindsey , too . - What ? Karen .
We didn 't know for sure . I didn 't know what to tell you .
Mom , I just want you to be okay .
Listen , I just want you to know , when he gets here ,
I 'm gonna fucking kill him , because 40 years ago ,
- when I was a kid , you protected me . - Yeah .
So , tonight , I 'm gonna protect you . Okay ?
Nurse . You know , I appreciate you ,
but could you get out , please ?
Like , get out now !
We had him .
How did he escape ?
I don 't know . I don 't know .
TOMMY : What do we do ? We don 't have the police support .
We fight .
We always fight .
- Go ! Find him , Tommy ! - Yeah . I will . I will .
- LAURIE : I ... No . ( groans ) - Mom , don 't . Don 't .
I need you to listen to me .
You need to listen to me right now , okay ?
All right , a lifetime of preparation , and for what ?
Ray is dead .
So many people are dead .
We 're not equipped .
Allyson 's run off with crazy Lonnie Elam .
People are losing their minds .
There are authorities who are trained
to deal with exactly this kind of ... this ...
There 's a system .
Well , the system failed .
Now , get the fuck out of my way .
- Don 't . No . No . - No , no , no . Get away .
- What are you doing ? - Karen , no !
- Stop right now ! - Get away !
I am not gonna let you do this .
- No . Mom . - Get out of my way .
- Move ! - Mom , please , what are you doing ?
Do you even know what that is ?
( panting )
It makes the pain go away .
( screams )
( syringe drops to floor )
Let him come for me .
No .
Let him take my head as I take his .
- No . - Maybe the only way he can die
is if I die , too .
- No . - Karen , you and Allyson
should not have to keep running
because of the darkness that I created , honey .
So you just have to let me go .
- Karen , move ! - Mom , stop . Stop , Mom .
Listen . Mom .
Stop .
I am not gonna let anything happen to you .
( panting )
We want to get married .
Um ...
Uh , I-I guess , uh , right away .
Right away , yeah . Right away .
The waggle dance is how bees communicate .
They share the information where the flower is
with the rest of the colony .
They communicate the precise location
by shaking their butts .
( chuckles ) What is in that honey ?
WOMAN ( on TV ) : Hey , Mom , he wants to talk to you .
Hello , Mom . Seymour Moskowitz .
Right . Jewish .
My mom kept bees before she died .
I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry , baby .
( knocking )
And now they 're at the back door .
Halloween 's over , kids !
( knocking )
I 'll handle it .
( turns off TV )
Knock it off !
( crickets chirping )
( knocking )
Well , now they 're at the front door .
( sighs )
Let 's scare the shit out of these kids .
( Big John sighs )
John .
Don 't you know whose house this was ?
Huh ?
Honey , don 't do anything stupid .
We don 't want to get sued .
I bet those bitches are in the bushes .
Did you lock the back door ?
Uh ...
I 'll check .
Next time , I 'm coming with a pitchfork .
( shudders )
Big John ?
Yes , Little John ?
( whispers ) : Someone 's in our house .
And it 's not a child .
Fuck that .
I got this knife .
( slow , heavy footsteps )
- ( clamoring ) - LEIGH : Fuck off , man .
Get out of my face .
Lonnie , where are you ?
I 'm at the hospital right now .
Yeah , I brought her in to E.R.
( whispers ) : Is that him ?
( whispers ) : I saw that guy on TV .
Back , back , back .
( indistinct chatter )
You know what I mean ?
( clamoring )
I have no answer for you .
Help me .
Help me !
( clamoring continues )
Tommy , what 's happening ?
- I don 't know . - Who is it ?
Um ...
- Help me ! - TOMMY : Who is it ? Is it Michael ?
- Is it him ? - I don 't know . - WOMAN : It 's Michael .
MAN : Michael 's here .
WOMAN : He 's not wearing his mask !
- TOMMY : It 's Michael . - Michael !
Michael ! Stop !
( clamoring )
TOMMY : Stop !
Mom , Mom , you 're not going near him .
- I 'm gonna go . - No , you 're not .
Block the doorway !
Don 't let him leave !
- He 's getting away . - Tommy , get him !
Excuse me .
- Evil dies tonight ! - ( clamoring continues )
- ( chanting ) : Evil dies tonight ! - KAREN : Come on !
Evil dies tonight ! Evil dies tonight !
Evil dies tonight !
♪ ♪
Little John ?
LITTLE JOHN : Big John .
Yeah .
Little John ?
Big John .
Little John , the study 's clear .
( gasps softly )
( breath trembling )
( gasps )
( shudders , gasps )
( groans )
( knife clatters in other room )
- ( Big John groaning ) - ( clattering )
( screams )
Big John !
( body thuds )
( panting )
( crying ) : Big John .
No .
Big John .
( gasps )
Michael .
You 've come home .
♪ ♪
LITTLE JOHN : No !
( clamoring )
( panting , whimpering )
LAURIE : No , no , no , that 's not ...
- That 's not him . It 's not him ! - It 's not him ? It 's not him !
- That 's not Michael ! - It 's not him !
- It 's not him ! It 's not him ! - MAN : Get him !
It 's not him !
You fucking sheep , it 's not him !
- It 's not him ! It 's not him ! - Get out of the way !
( grunts , groans )
( Laurie wheezing )
Mom , Mom , Mom !
Mom . Mom .
- Mom . Mom ! - ( groaning )
I got to get you out of here .
Tommy !
MAN : Get back here !
KAREN : Help ! Help !
Somebody help me !
( Karen shouting indistinctly )
- ( Laurie groaning ) - KAREN : Mom ! Okay .
Okay . Okay , be careful .
( groaning )
- I got it , Sheriff . - KAREN : You 're gonna be okay .
- KAREN : Come on . - WOMAN : Get him !
- LAURIE : It 's not him . - KAREN : I know , Mom .
I got her . I got her . Go , go , go .
- It 's ... not him . - Your arm .
- All right , let 's get her ... - They 're after the wrong guy .
- Let 's get her into bed . - It 's not him . It 's not Michael .
- ( clamoring ) - Get out of the way !
Okay , Mom . Come on .
- We got you . - ( door closes )
GRAHAM : All right , gentle . Careful .
- Careful . I can handle this . - ( groaning )
Be careful of your head .
( panting ) : Okay . All right .
- Are you okay ? - Yeah .
All right , look , stay here .
There 's gonna be guards outside the door , all right ?
- Be careful . - I 'm gonna get a nurse to get you
- all hooked up again , okay ? - You be careful .
Hospital staff sightings on the second floor .
( panting )
Please stop !
Please ! It 's not Michael !
You don 't know what he looks like !
GRAHAM : We 're in the stairwell . Move !
Watch it , asshole . Karen .
You okay ? Here , move over to the side .
To the side with them . Careful , careful .
- TOMMY : He 's up there ! - Stop ! It 's not him !
- Get out of my way ! - Tommy , stop ! Chill out .
Get a grip , Tommy !
MAN : Get the fuck out of the way !
- BARKER : Knock it off ! - ( yelling )
( clamoring )
- Tommy ! - ( screaming )
WOMAN : We 're gonna kill him !
CROWD ( chanting in distance ) : Evil dies tonight !
- It 's all happening . - ( chant continues )
Michael 's masterpiece .
He created this chaos , but ...
I 'm the one that brought it all onto Haddonfield .
I could have made all this go away .
It was that night that you were attacked .
It 's not your fault .
It 's mine .
HAWKINS : It was an accident .
I was lost in my own regret .
Did Michael kill again ?
HAWKINS : I saw the look
in Loomis 's eyes .
All he wanted was more blood .
More death .
And I couldn 't take it .
And then in that moment , all I could think was that
inside that monster , there was somebody 's baby boy .
LOOMIS : Purely and simply evil .
( distorted , echoing ) : No ! Don 't !
I could have made all this go away .
It 's not your fault .
It 's mine .
But now I know
there 's nothing inside that man but pure evil .
It 's not just Michael .
It 's what he 's done to this town , these people .
Decent people .
You 're a good man , Frank .
You were doing your job .
But now it needs to die .
' Cause every time somebody 's afraid ,
the Boogeyman wins .
It needs to die .
And I 'm the one that needs to kill it .
- ( crowd clamoring ) - ( panting )
( panting )
It 's not you .
I know it 's not you .
I 'm not gonna hurt you .
♪ ♪
I know you 're scared .
They 're scared , too .
I 'm not gonna let them hurt you .
( panting )
KAREN : Okay .
- Okay . I know . I know . - ( whimpering )
I 'm gonna help you . I 'm gonna help you .
Okay , come on . Come on .
( clamoring )
Let go of my hand .
That 's good .
I 'm gonna lock these doors .
Okay .
Okay . Lock this behind me .
They 're coming .
- Come on ! - ( clamoring continues )
( footsteps thundering )
I 'm not gonna let them hurt you .
It 's him .
Get him ! Get him !
♪ ♪
CROWD : Evil dies tonight !
Evil dies tonight !
- ( whimpering ) - Evil dies tonight !
♪ ♪
Evil dies tonight !
Evil dies tonight ! Evil dies tonight !
( muffled ) : Stop them !
It 's not him ?
( groans )
♪ ♪
( clamoring )
( screaming )
- TOMMY : Move ! - Evil dies tonight !
Evil dies tonight !
- ( gasping , murmuring ) - ( chant continues in distance )
- WOMAN : Oh , my God . - MAN : He 's dead .
( people gasping )
- Oh , my God . - Yeah .
Evil dies tonight !
( murmuring )
♪ ♪
Leigh ! Leigh !
LEIGH : No . It 's not him .
It 's not him , Tommy .
He 's always worn a mask . How do we know it 's not him ?
How do we know , Leigh ?
( Tommy panting )
Now he 's turning us into monsters .
♪ ♪
( quiet chatter )
( camera clicks )
I swear I was just trying to do the right thing .
Look at me .
What I 'm thinking is the killer was choking him ,
Pete went for his gun .
As he pulled it up , it went off .
Give me your gun .
Don 't look at it .
Just be cool and give me your gun .
Take this .
It was an accident .
He shot himself .
Got it ?
Just because your intentions are good
doesn 't mean things always work out .
I stood in the way .
It was me .
- It wasn 't him . - Let me find him , then .
He 's after me .
No , he 's not .
LAURIE : Frank .
- ( groans ) - HAWKINS : He 's not .
It was the doctor that took him to your house tonight .
It wasn 't Michael .
It 's not about you .
- Doctor , get back in the car ! - No !
I 'm still gonna blow this motherfucker 's brains out .
( grunts )
Mom ! Mom !
Help !
He 's a six-year-old boy with the strength of a man
and the mind of an animal .
I know . I 've seen his face .
I looked in his eyes when I took off his mask .
Did you know that when he was a little boy
he used to stand in his sister 's bedroom and ...
stare out the window ?
My partner died
the night he stood on that same spot .
But for an instant ,
before his death , he knew .
Maybe he wasn 't looking out .
Maybe he was looking in .
At his reflection .
At himself .
Who knows what makes him kill , what motivates him ?
But in his heart , it always seemed to me
he wants one thing .
He 's going home .
- He went from Laurie 's compound ... - Mm-hmm .
... the victims in her neighborhood ,
to the park , okay ?
If you track those locations , that 's a straight line ,
basically an arrow pointing straight
to Lampkin Lane , Michael 's childhood home .
I came face-to-face with this asshole when I was a kid .
He creeps , he kills , he goes home .
Then that 's where we 're going .
LONNIE : Yeah .
♪ ♪
Karen . Karen .
Listen , I 'm sorry .
You were right , okay ? I 'm sorry .
Tommy , you took my daughter to chase a killer ,
and an innocent man is dead .
Fuck it . None of us are innocent .
Karen , listen . Listen . I fucked up .
I fucked up . I 'm sorry .
So , what now ?
You 're sorry ? You 're just gonna stand here hating yourself ?
No .
I got to keep trying .
But if I go down ,
I 'm gonna go down swinging .
I need a car .
I have a car .
♪ ♪
( engine shuts off )
Okay , so the key is we stick together .
No , I 'm going in alone .
- What ? - ALLYSON : Mr. Elam .
You fucking dummy , you brought your kid
- to the belly of the beast . - Dad , no .
Mr. Elam , with all due respect ,
you really expect me to sit here while you go inside
and confront the man that killed my father ?
No , I don 't expect you to .
But I 'm asking , Allyson .
For your sake and my son 's .
Okay ? Just stay here .
You see anything suspicious , you honk the horn , all right ?
But you stay safe .
All right ?
I will see you at the finish line , buddy .
( door opens )
( door closes )
( takes deep breath )
( knocks )
( panting quietly )
( creaking )
Okay .
♪ ♪
ALLYSON : This is so fucked up .
- ( gunshot ) - Cameron , let 's go .
Come on .
Go , go , go , go !
( both panting )
ALLYSON : Okay .
( gun cocks )
Dad ?
- ( panting ) - ( floorboards creaking )
CAMERON ( whispers ) : Allyson .
Over there .
( both panting )
( breathing heavily )
( gasping breaths )
( sighing )
( creaking footsteps )
( " Could I Have This Dance " by Anne Murray plays in distance )
♪ I 'll always remember ♪
♪ The song they were playing ♪
♪ The first time we danced ♪
♪ And I knew ♪
♪ As we swayed to the music ♪
♪ And held to each other ♪
♪ I fell in love with you ♪
♪ Could I have this dance ♪
- ♪ For the rest of my life ? ♪ - ( Allyson gasping )
- ♪ Would you be my partner ♪ - ( shudders , whimpers )
♪ Every night ? ♪
- ♪ When we 're together ♪ - ( breathing heavily )
♪ It feels so right ♪
♪ Could I have this dance ♪
♪ For the rest of my life ? ♪
( shudders )
( panting )
( trembling breaths )
♪ I 'll always remember ♪
♪ That magic moment ♪
♪ When I held you close ♪
- ♪ To me ♪ - ( cocks gun )
- ( trembling breaths ) - ( floorboards creaking softly )
♪ As we moved together ♪
♪ I knew forever ♪
♪ You 're all I 'll ever need ... ♪
( gasps softly , pants )
( shuddering )
( Cameron gasps )
( whimpers ) : Dad .
( screaming )
Cameron ?
( pained grunting )
♪ ♪
( grunts , whimpers )
( yells in pain )
CAMERON : Allyson !
Cameron !
( shudders , grunts )
( knife drops to floor )
( screams )
Cameron !
No !
- Cameron ! No ! - ( wheezing )
Cameron !
( groans )
ALLYSON ( whimpering ) : No .
No , no , no , no !
- ( screams ) - No !
- Allyson ! - No !
( Cameron gasping )
( Allyson sobs )
Come and get me , motherfucker !
Come and get me .
( shuddering )
( groaning weakly )
( Allyson screaming )
- ( Allyson sobbing ) - ( Cameron wheezing )
♪ ♪
Leave him alone !
No .
No . No !
- ( neck snaps ) - ( sobbing ) : No !
( Allyson sobbing )
No !
( Allyson grunting )
( whimpers )
Do it . Do it .
Do it !
( screams )
( grunts )
( pitchfork clatters )
- ( grunts ) - ( Allyson screams )
( panting )
( trembling ) : Mom .
( gasps )
Mom .
- ( gasps ) - ( Allyson sobbing )
No , Mom .
You want your mask ?
Come and get it !
You want to fucking kill someone , take me !
Mom . No , Mom .
I 'm an innocent woman ,
just like your sister was .
It was Halloween night .
She was in her bedroom .
And it was right here .
Your house .
Can 't you feel it ?
ALLYSON ( whimpering ) : No . No , Mom .
( Karen gasping )
Mom , no .
Mom !
( panting , whimpering )
♪ ♪
Gotcha .
( tires squeal )
LEIGH : Hey , Michael .
It 's Halloween .
Everyone 's entitled to one good scare .
( panting )
♪ ♪
- MAN : Light him up . - MAN 2 : Let 's take him .
( grunting )
- ( gun fires ) - ( man screams )
- ( breathing heavily ) - ( people grunting )
( all panting )
We got this , Karen .
Go be with your daughter .
( grunts fiercely )
♪ ♪
LAURIE : I always thought Michael Myers
was flesh and blood , just like you and me ,
but a mortal man could not have survived
what he 's lived through .
The more he kills ,
the more he transcends
into something else impossible to defeat .
Fear .
People are afraid .
That is the true curse of Michael .
He 'll always be here , won 't he ?
Even when we can 't see him .
You can 't defeat it with brute force .
If we only knew then what we know now .
( gun clicking )
- ( bone cracks ) - ( screams )
( screams )
LAURIE : It is the essence of evil .
The anchor that divides us .
It is the terror that grows stronger when we try to hide .
( yells )
( pained gasp )
♪ ♪
( gasping weakly )
LAURIE : If they don 't stop him tonight ,
maybe we 'll find him tomorrow .
Or next Halloween ,
when the sun sets and someone is alone .
( quiet chatter )
( siren wails )
♪ ♪
You can 't close your eyes and pretend he isn 't there .
LAURIE : Because he is .
( inhales deeply )
( exhales )
( muffled , distorted scream )
♪ ♪
( breathing heavily )
( John Carpenter 's Halloweentheme playing )
♪ ♪
( theme ends )
( " Hunter 's Moon " by Ghost playing )
♪ It 's been a long time coming ♪
♪ I 'm coming back for you , my friend ♪
♪ To where we hide as children ♪
♪ Though my memories are faded , they ♪
♪ Come back to haunt me once again ♪
♪ And though my mind is somewhat jaded now ♪
♪ It 's time for me to strike again ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ It 's a hunter 's moon ♪
♪ Under a headstone , sister ♪
♪ I 'm dying to see you , my friend ♪
♪ Like any old cemetery ♪
♪ Though my memories are faded , they ♪
♪ Come back to haunt me once again ♪
♪ And though my mind is somewhat jaded now ♪
♪ It 's time for me to strike again ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ It 's a hunter 's moon ♪
( indistinct chanting vocal )
♪ ♪
♪ Though my memories are faded , they ♪
♪ Come back to haunt me once again ♪
♪ And though my mind is somewhat jaded now ♪
♪ It 's time for me to strike again ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ It 's a hunter 's moon ♪
♪ Hunter 's moon . ♪
( song ends )